谢了
Thanks.
真见鬼了 我居然有条留言
That's weird. I have a message.
是见鬼了
That's weird.
你居然还有台答录机
You still have an answering machine.
泰德 我是船长啊
Ted, this is the Captain.
请您尽快回电
Please call me back at your earliest convenience.
唉 这下坏了
Oh, crap.
老爸\N　　　  　　 老妈\N　　 　　 浪漫史\N　　  　　　　第八季  第十六集\N
S08E16 The Ashtray
翻译:  @神RoyShiCheng @CIA_Kevin @rubik2011\N@苏赛崽 @阿狸小H\N校对: @园丁姐姐Vinata @神RoyShiCheng\N统筹+后期: @神RoyShiCheng @苏赛崽
HIMYM字幕组 倾情奉献
孩子们 你们还记得船长吧
Kids, you remember the Captain.
他是全纽约最富的人之一
He was one of the richest men in New York,
我们刚认识的时候 他和佐伊还是夫妻
and when I met him, he was married to Zoey,
最后 我和佐伊以"朋友"告终
who I ended up... befriending.
-天哪 他像是气疯了  -有吗
-Oh, man, he seems pissed. -Does he?
有 自己听
Yes. Listen.
泰德 我是船长啊
Ted, this is the Captain.
请您尽快回电
Please call me back at your earliest convenience.
好吧 我听出来了
Oh, I hear it now.
有吗 我还是没发现啊
What? I don't know.
再听一遍
Listen again.
泰德 我是船长啊
Ted, this is the Captain.
请您尽快 回电
Please call me back at your earliest convenience.
他听上去是气疯了
He sounds pissed.
对吧 我明白为什么了
Yeah, and I think I know why.
肯定和我们上次见面脱离不了干系
It has to do with the last time I saw him.
那是 呃...一年半前的事儿了
It was, um... it was, like, a year and a half ago.
天哪 那事真是太疯狂了
Oh, boy, that was a crazy story.
天哪 还真是
Oh, boy, yeah.
记忆犹新呢
I remember.
你不在场啊
You weren't there.
泰德 你坏死了啦
Ted, bubbeleh.
每当你们发生点什么疯狂的事情 我都在场的
If you have a crazy story, I was there.
这可是宇宙真理
That's just a law of the universe.
那发生了什么
So what happened?
呃 我和佐伊分手 刚过几个星期
Well, it was a few weeks after Zoey and I broke up,
我还处于恢复期
and I was on the rebound,
然后我又和那个叫贝琪的妞 交往了一阵子
and I kind of rekindled things with that girl, Becky.
-贝琪是谁  -大船小船大小船
-Becky? -Boats, boats, boats.
大船小船大小船
Boats, boats, boats!
船船船
Boats!
再说一遍 这广告是关于什么的
What's this a commercial for again?
我不太能理解...
I can't quite...
大船 小船 大小船
Boats, boats, boats!
我去 进房间里搞 你们两个
Oh, get a room, you two.
你不在场
You weren't there.
我也在的 好吗
I was, too.
好啊 既然你在 后来怎样 你来说
All right, you were there? Tell me the story.
人家还是喜欢你来说啦
I like the way you tell it.
你来 拜托啦
Please, I insist.
好吧 我们一起说吧
Okay, we'll tell it together.
也行
Okay.
-莉莉...  -莉莉...
-Lily... -Lily...
-邀请我们...  -邀请我们...
-had invited us... -had invited us...
去一个艺术
...to an art...
Art也作人名Arthur的缩写
加芬克尔的演唱会
...Garfunkel concert.
Art Garfunkel美国男声重唱组合西蒙和加芬克尔的成员之一
画廊的开业典礼
...gallery opening.
一个亚瑟•加芬克尔画廊的开业演唱会
An Art Garfunkel gallery opening concert.
不要停 泰德 你太棒了
Go on, Ted. You're doing great.
总之
Anyway,
我去了画廊
I get to the gallery...
这地方真豪华
This place is so fancy.
这种场合最好别丢人
I hope I don't embarrass myself.
什么 莉莉 得了吧
What? Lily, come on.
你有什么好让人丢脸的
You got nothing to be embarrassed about.
哥们 看那是谁
Dude, look who it is.
然后他就出现了...
And who should walk in but...
爹地回家了
Daddy's home.
不是你
Nope.
看啊泰德•莫斯比 我的老冤家
Well, well, Ted Mosby, my old nemesis.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
呃 就是 莉莉看到广告上提到这个...
Um, well, uh, Lily saw an ad for this...
画廊
Gallery?
所以 我们就来这里看看...
So we... we came to check out the...
艺术品
Artwork.
然后我们就撞见...
And then we ran into...
我
Me.
天哪 这家伙太粗鲁了
Man, this guy's so rude.
我知道他为什么那么生气
I mean, I get why he's mad.
我确实和他前妻厮混过 好多次了
I did stick it to his ex-wife... repeatedly.
不过呢 这家伙真是个魂淡
Still, he's being a jerk.
总得有人灭灭他的威风
Someone needs to bring him down a peg.
抱歉 去哪儿了 我的...
I'm sorry. Where are my...
礼貌
Manners.
以其人之道 还治其人之身
That's how that feels.
这位是我的艺术顾问
This is my art consultant.
谢莉
Shelly.
艺术顾问 是干什么的
Art consultant? What's that?
是这样的 谢莉帮船长挑选艺术作品
Oh, Shelly helps the Captain
通过审评作品价值
select artwork based on its aesthetic appeal
协助船长投资
and value as an investment.
老子要杀了你
因此 我认为她会喜欢上
That's why I think she's gonna love
这幅大象画
this elephant painting.
我觉得这个画家前途无量
I think this artist is going places.
我先告辞了
Well, I should go.
船长 我们明天再谈
Captain, we'll talk tomorrow?
你随意
At ease.
嗨 你们要是喜欢艺术的话
Hey, if you like art,
来看看我刚入手的那幅画吧
you should see the painting I just acquired.
就在我楼上的公寓里
It's in my apartment just upstairs.
一定会拿下你的
It's gonna blow you away.
能花钱买这种烟灰缸的人
Anyone with this kind of ashtray money
没准自己就有个岛 以狩猎人类为乐
probably has an island where he hunts people.
也许就在加勒比海上
Probably somewhere in the Caribbean.
我估计那儿还是潜水胜地什么的
I bet there's good snorkeling.
你好吗 我的亲 我的肝 我生命的四分之三
Hello, my darling, my one true love, my everything.
嗯 谁想看那幅画
So, who wants to see that painting?
好吧 船长 我们知道你为什么叫我们上来
Okay, Captain, we know why you brought us up here.
是因为我和佐伊的事情
It's, uh... it's about me and Zoey.
泰德
Ted,
你有什么想说的
if you've got something to say,
就说吧
say it.
一把鱼枪
A harpoon gun?
一把双筒鱼枪
A double-barreled harpoon gun.
单筒
One barrel.
带着瞄准镜
With a scope.
没有瞄准镜
No scope.
我知道你生气 船长 但是我向你保证
I know you're upset, Captain, but I promise you
在你和佐伊分手以前
nothing happened between me and Zoey
我们什么事都没有
until after you guys split up, okay?
所以
So let's...
我们 就 就 就把这玩意儿放下
Let's please, just-just-just put this down.
好吧 真乖 就这样
Okay? Okay, oh, there we go.
是这样的 泰德
Look, Ted,
我没有生你的气
I'm not mad at you.
事实上 我爱上别人了
The truth is I'm in love
我们那事就算了
with somebody else now, so we're fine.
你只要别把现在这位也抢走就行 好吗
Just don't steal this one from me, too, okay?
好吗
Okay?
当然
Of course.
我保证 好的
I promise. Okay.
但我还是好奇
But that got me thinking.
谁会是他的新爱人呢
Who was this new lady in his life?
我有一种不祥的预感
I-I had this weird sinking feeling.
我们都有
We both did.
我得看看那照片
I had to see that picture.
所以 我等到所有人
So I waited until everyone
都离开房间 然后
was out of the room, and then...
船 船 船
Boats, boats, boats!
不
No.
不要啊
No...!
她是小船船 而他是船长
She's "Boats, boats, boats," And he's the Captain.
倒挺配的 真为他们俩高兴
That's sweet; I'm happy for those two.
泰德你都弱爆了
Ted, you suck.
哦 天啊 哦 天啊
Oh, my God, oh, my God.
他打的 他打来了 我该怎么办
It's him, it's him. What do I do?
-我该怎么办  -泰德 等等
What do I do? -Ted, wait a second.
-我该怎么办 -等等 先给我等一下
-What do I do? -Wait a second. Wait a second!
嘿 有没有可能 他打电话
Hey, is there any chance that he is calling
是为了叫我们出去上他的船上玩
to invite the three of us out on his boat?
呃 我不知道 1%的可能性吧
Uh, I don't know, maybe like one percent.
泰德的手机 马上转接到泰德
Ted's phone. Hold for Ted.
你好
Hello.
泰德 我要问你一些事情
Ted, I'm gonna ask you something,
我需要你百分百诚实地回答
and I want you to be completely honest.
罗宾的电话是多少
What's your friend Robin's number?
什么
What?
泰德 问问船的事情
Ted, ask about the boat.
呃 船长 你 你能等一下吗
Uh, Captain, can... can I put you on hold?
没问题
Affirmative.
他想要罗宾的电话号码
He wants Robin's number.
我该给他吗
Should I give it to him?
他想勾引我的未婚妻
Is he trying to hook up with my fiancee?
不 绝对不行
No, uh-uh.
这种情况发生只能在
The only way that's happening
我也偷情的情况下
is if I get to hook up with someone, too.
等等...不
Wait a second... No.
除非.. 绝对不行
Unless... Absolutely not.
但是... 我在想什么
However... Forget it.
再说了...雅蠛蝶
On the other hand... Ixnay!
同志们啊 同志们 我得做个决定
Guys, guys, I got to make a decision here.
这样 我建议 把电话给他
Okay, you know what, I say do it.
如果他打给罗宾约炮
If it is a booty call,
罗宾会委婉地拒绝他
then Robin will just let him down easy,
但同时 泰德又会受到船长的喜爱
but in the meantime, Ted is back on the Captain's good side.
我们都能上他的船上玩 我还能掌掌舵
We all get to go out on his boat; I get to steer it.
一箭N雕啊
Everybody wins.
有道理
Okay.
好吧 把号码给他吧
Fine. Give him her number.
她不会介意吗
You don't think she'll mind?
肯定不会
I don't think she'll mind.
你把我的号码给了船长
You gave the Captain my number?
嗯 她介意了
She minds.
难道你不记得了吗
Do you not remember
那晚我们在艺术展上遇到了他
that night we hung out with him at the art show?
哦 是啊 当然你不记得
Oh, right, of course you don't remember
因为 那天早些时候
because, earlier that night,
你和贝琪一起分享了一个超大号的三明治
you shared a big, fat sandwich with Becky.
三明治暗指大麻 你懂的
大船 小船 大小船
Boats, boats, boats!
这广告什么意思啊
What's this a commercial for again?
是啊 所以呢
Yeah, so?
我不觉得这有多大关系
I hardly think that changes the story.
嗯 嗯
Mmm. Mmm.
真好吃
Delicious!
这个地方真豪华
This place is so fancy.
这种场合你最好别丢人
I hope I don't embarrass myself.
哦 别这样啊 莉莉
Oh, come on, Lily.
你有什么好让人丢脸的
You got nothing to be embarrassed about.
兄弟 看看谁来了
Dude, look who's here.
爹地回来了
Daddy's home.
不是你
Nope.
看啊
Well, well.
泰德•莫斯比 我的老冤家
Ted Mosby, my old nemesis.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
呃 莉莉
Well, Lily...
看见 一张 广告 提到这个
saw an ad for this...
画廊
Gallery.
我们想 呃
So we thought we'd, um...
过来看看这些
come and check out the...
艺术品
Artwork?
结果我们撞见了
And then we ran into...
我
Me?
船长根本没在看你
And the Captain wasn't glaring at you.
他的眼神黏在...
He couldn't take his eyes off...
嘿 再次见到你真好
Hey, nice to see you again.
我也是
Yeah, you, too.
哦
Oh.
这家伙太粗鲁了
Man, this guy is so rude.
我知道他为什么那么生气
I mean, I get why he's upset.
我确实和他前妻厮混过 好多次了
I did stick it to his ex-wife... repeatedly.
不过呢
Still,
这家伙真是个魂淡
the guy's being a jerk.
总得有人灭灭他的威风
Someone needs to take him down a peg.
抱歉
Sorry.
失态了
Where are my manners?
这是谢莉 我的艺术顾问
This is Shelly, my art consultant.
艺术顾问 干什么的
Art consultant? What's that?
谢莉帮船长挑选艺术
Shelly helps the Captain select artwork
通过评审作品...
based on aesthetic...
礼貌
Manners!
以其人之道 还治其人之身
That's how that feels.
以便
...appeal
协助船长投资
and value as an investment,
所以我觉得她会喜欢
and that's why I think she's gonna love
这幅大象画
this elephant painting.
我觉得这个画家前途无量
I think this artist is going places.
我先告辞了
Well, I should go.
船长 我们明天再谈
Captain, we'll talk tomorrow.
你们要是喜欢艺术的话
If you like art,
来看看我刚入手的那幅画吧
you should see the painting I just acquired.
一定会拿下你的
It's gonna blow you away.
潜水ing
Snorkeling.
然后 在我拯救了差点被你摔破的
Then, after I saved you from destroying
价值连城的水晶烟灰缸后...
a priceless crystal ashtray...
不用谢
You're welcome.
你好吗 我的亲 我的肝 我生命的四分之三
Hello, my darling, my one true love, my everything.
啊嗬
Ahoy?
Ahoy是航海时的呼号声
想看看那幅画吗
So who wants to see that painting?
好吧 船长
Okay, Captain.
我们知道你叫我们来
We all know why you brought us up here.
是因为我和...呃...
This is about me and, um...
佐伊
Zoey.
好吧 泰德
All right, Ted.
你有什么想说的
If you've got something to say,
就说吧
say it.
哇哦 哇哦
Whoa, whoa.
遥控器吗
A remote control?
是遥控器
A remote control.
放松点
Let's relax.
我 我知道你生气 船长
I-I know you're upset, Captain.
我 我只是 我向你保证
I-I just... I want to assure you
你和佐伊分手以前
nothing happened between me and Zoey
我们什么事都没有
until after you guys had split up.
所以请你 请你
So let's just... let's just...
把这玩意儿放下
let's put this down.
很好 真乖
Okay, okay.
就这样
There we go.
泰德 我没有生你的气
Ted, I'm not mad at you.
其实 我爱上别人了
Truth is, I'm in love with somebody else now.
就这样 他请我去他卧室
So he invited me back to his bedroom
看那幅画 结果
to show me this painting, and...
终于
Finally.
就剩我俩了
We're alone.
罗宾 别 我不要去想象那个画面
Robin, no, I don't want to picture that.
什么都没发生
Nothing happened.
哦 那就是说有手工活了
Aw, that means hand stuff.
什么 才没有
What? No.
我是认真的 他还在恢复期
I'm serious-- he was on the rebound.
我让他慢慢找回自己
I told him to take some time to pull himself together and...
一年半后再打给我
call me in a year and a half.
啊 真好
Ah, great.
如果他约你出去怎么办
What if he asks you out?
我们的感情怎么办
What does that mean for our relationship?
难不成你要来段引领潮流的
What, are we planning to be in some super-enlightened,
前卫的婚姻
forward-thinking marriage,
不想被吊死在沉闷又过时的
where we don't get hung up on the suffocating
一夫一妻制上
and outdated principles of monogamy,
享受下万花丛中的乐趣
and instead enjoy the company of multiple partners,
偶尔也带其他人滚滚我们的婚床
sometimes bringing said partners into our marital bed,
只带女生 男生免进
but just girls, not dudes,
偶尔也可带次男生试试感觉
except maybe one time just to see what that's like?
这就是你想要的吗
I mean, is that what you want?
不
No.
好吧
Okay.
我也不想
Me, neither!
罗宾 听我说 你得给船长打电话
Okay, Robin, look, you-you need to call the Captain
委婉地拒绝他 好吗
and let him down easy, okay?
让他过自己的生活
Let him move on with his life.
让他和老朋友们 开着小船出去玩
Let him go out on his boat with his old friends,
也许还有些新朋友一起
maybe some new friends.
最好让他的某个新朋友也掌掌舵
Maybe let one of those new friends steer the boat.
这样的话 那个新朋友就有机会说
Just so that one of them could say,
前方有冰山
"Iceberg straighthead!"
模仿泰坦尼克号情节
好吧
Fine.
啊嗬
Ahoy.
嗨 船长 我是罗宾
Hi. Captain, it's Robin.
啊嗬
Ahoy.
呃
Uh, look,
我 呃 不得不告诉你
I, uh, have to be upfront with you.
我已经订婚了
I'm engaged.
订婚 我以为你和马修结婚了
Engaged? I thought you were married to Marshall.
你是罗宾吗
This is Robin right?
红发的幼儿园老师
The redheaded kindergarten teacher
画展那天穿灰裙蓝鞋的那个
who wore the gray dress and the blue shoes to that art show?
你等一下行吗
Can you please hold a moment?
抛锚等待中
Dropping anchor.
他要找的是莉莉
He's looking for Lily.
我能给他号码吗
Should I give him her number?
可以 我们已经谈过了
Yeah. We've already discussed it.
也就四百万的事儿
It's four million cash.
哦 她的电话号码
Oh, her phone number.
可以 她不会介意的
Yes, I don't think she'll mind.
你把我的电话给船长了
You gave the Captain my number?
嗯 她介意了
She minds.
现世报终于来了
It finally happened.
过去阴影找上我了
My past finally caught up with me.
哦 天哪
Oh, God.
莉莉 如果你告诉我
Lily, if you tell me that you
你和船长上过床 而且讲不出一个
slept with the Captain for anything under 2.8,
让我们底线之内能接受的理由的话...
which we agreed was as low as we were going to go...
不 不是那样的
No, it's nothing like that.
你们记得我们上次见船长的事吗
Do you guys remember the last time we saw the Captain?
-记得  -哦 好吧
-Yes. -Oh, right.
你当然不记得 巴尼 你当时没在
Of course you don't. Barney, you weren't there.
泰德 你那时候刚刚过完三明治瘾
Ted, you had just floated out of a Snoop Dogg B-side.
罗宾 你刚在聚会上
And, Robin, you had just come from that
玩过了头
big meeting that ran long.
好美味 再来一个虾虾
Delicious. Shrimpy for me.
这地方真豪华
This place is so fancy.
这种场合你们最好别丢人
I hope I don't embarrass myself.
拜托 莉莉 你有什么好让人丢脸的
Come on, Lily, you have nothing to be embarrassed about.
兄弟
Dude!
看看谁来了
Look who's here!
爹地回...
Daddy's...
不是你
Nope.
看啊
Well, well.
泰德•莫斯比 我的老冤家
Ted Mosby, my old nemesis.
你好啊 水手君
Hello, sailor.
不
No!
不×10
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
好吧 我承认那是真的
Okay, yeah, that's what happened.
这是谢莉 我的艺术顾问
This is Shelly, my art consultant.
艺术顾问
Art consultant!
那是什么啊
What's that?
谢莉帮船长挑选艺术作品
Shelly helps the Captain select artwork
通过审评作品价值 协助船长投资
based on its aesthetic appeal and its value as an investment,
所以我觉得她一定会喜欢这幅大象画的
which is why I think she's gonna love this elephant painting.
我觉得这个画家前途无量
I think this artist is going places.
不喜欢这幅画的人肯定是个大傻子
You'd have to be a real Dumbo not to enjoy this painting.
懂了吗
Get it?
因为他是个大象画啊
'Cause he's an elephant?
你的笑点和你的艺术品位一样低
Your sense of humor is as good as your taste in art.
船长先生
Captain?
我们明天再谈吧
We'll talk tomorrow?
如果你要是喜欢艺术的话
If you like art,
来看看我刚入手的那幅吧
you should see the painting I just acquired.
它在我的...
It's in my...
礼貌
Manners.
以其人之道 还治其人之身
That's how that feels.
在我楼上的公寓里
In my apartment right upstairs.
一定会征服你们的
It's gonna blow you away.
潜水ing
Snorkeling.
在我拯救了差点你摔破的
Then, after I saved you from destroying
价值连城的水晶烟灰缸后
a priceless crystal ashtray...
不用谢
You're welcome.
你好吗 我的亲 我的肝 我生命的四分之三
Hello, my darling, my one true love, my everything.
谁想看看那幅画
So, who wants to see that painting?
哟 你给我看你的
Ooh, if you show me yours,
我也给你看我的
I'll show you mine.
于是我们去看画了
So we check out the painting.
哼 那幅大象画挂这里应该很好看
Huh. You know, that elephant painting would look nice in here.
眼前的可是大师级的杰作
You're looking at a masterpiece,
你却还在提那幅大象画吗
and you're talking about some elephant painting?
不要啊
No...!
哦 这幅也不错
Oh, this one's nice, too.
我只是更喜欢那幅大象画
I just like the elephant painting better.
听好 你喜欢什么根本就没人在意
You know, it doesn't matter what you like.
你只是个幼儿园老师而已
You're just a kindergarten teacher.
啊 终于就剩咱俩了
Ah, finally we're alone.
哦 不 莉莉 你做了些什么
Oh, no, Lily, what did you do?
他是个混蛋 他那宝贝画作活该被偷
He was a jerk-- he deserved to have that precious painting stolen.
哦 天哪 莉莉 你不会...
Oh, God, Lily, you didn't...?
我当然没有
Of course I didn't.
我偷了这个烟灰缸
I stole this ashtray instead.
-莉莉  -嘿 你知道规矩的
-Lily! -Hey, you know the rules.
表现不好一次 就收走玩具一只
You misbehave, I take away one of your toys.
这是艾尔德林的正义 小宝贝儿
Aldrin Justice, baby.
你说咱们家那个烟灰缸
So you're telling me that that ashtray
那个在咱家已经一年半的烟灰缸
that's been in our apartment for over a year and a half
不仅是偷的 还价值连城
is not only stolen, but also very expensive.
全部答对
Both of those things-- yes.
伙计们 让我们俩单独待会儿行吗
Guys, can you leave us alone for a minute, please?
哦 他们要干上了
Ooh, they're gonna do it.
不 我们要干架
No, we're gonna fight.
可能干完了架再会儿干那
And then maybe afterwards we'll do it.
居然是同一只烟灰缸
I can't believe that was the same ashtray.
我竟然没认出来
I should've recognized it.
是啊 我也没认出来
I know-- me, too.
巴尼 你当时不在
Barney, you weren't there.
你为啥非要成为故事的一部分啊
Why is it so important that you be part of this story?
因为疯疯狂狂就是我
Because crazy stories are my thing.
你有你的建筑
You have architecture,
马修有他的法律
Marshall has the law,
莉莉有她的艺术
Lily has art,
罗宾有她的相夫悦我之道
Robin has pleasing me sexually.
你们都有自己的激情
You all have a passion that drives you.
如果我有我的激情
Well, if I have a passion,
那就是让怒放的生命变成疯狂的故事
it's taking life and turning it into a series of crazy stories.
如果你没有我也能做到
If you can do that without me, then...
我都不知道我是谁了
I don't even know who I am anymore.
知道吗 巴尼
You know what, Barney?
我开始觉得
Now that I think about it,
你当时在场
you were there.
没错 你在呢
That's right, you were.
我在吗
I was?
我是说 我知道我在的呢
I mean, I know I was.
我就是这个意思 焚蛋们
That's what I'm saying, guys.
我们只是没发现你在那儿 因为...
We just, uh... we just didn't realize it because...
你乔装打扮了下
you were in disguise.
没错 你在那上演泡妞宝典里的一出呢
Yeah, you were doing, uh, one of your plays from the playbook.
对 谢莉 那个艺术顾问
On Shelly, the art consultant.
对 那是个关于艺术之类的招数
Yes, it was, uh, some play that had to do with art...
大芬维克的皇家大公爵吗
The Royal Archduke of Grand Fenwick?
一个只需两种居家常备物品 即可完成的简易招式
A simple play you can do using two everyday household objects--
一套普鲁士军装
a Prussian military costume
和一幅自己的油画
and an oil painting of yourself?
就是那个 而且对谢莉还很有效
That's the one, and it worked on Shelly.
我完全搞定她了
I totally nailed her!
而且之后我还搞定了她妹妹 那个更加火辣
And then I nailed her sister who was even hotter.
美好时光啊
Good times.
你得去还那个烟灰缸 你最好求老天保佑
You are gonna return that ashtray, and you're gonna pray
他不起诉你 要是咱俩之中有人进了监狱
that he doesn't press charges, because I can't be
这场婚姻就没法继续了
in a marriage where one of us is in prison.
我知道我们经常玩夫妻探访的角色扮演
I know that we role-play conjugal visits a lot,
不好意思 这就是终审结果
I'm sorry-- all rulings are final.
我不会把这个还他的
I am not taking it back.
天啊
Oh, my God!
莉莉
Lily,
到底有什么大不了的
what is the big deal?
好吧 那又怎样
Okay, so what?
就算他说你只是个幼儿园老师
So he said you're just a kindergarten teacher.
你为什么非要纠结这句话
Why do you let that bother you?
因为他说得没错
Because he was right.
我就是个小小的幼儿园老师
I am just a kindergarten teacher.
的确 我有一张艺术史的文凭
And, yes, I have a degree
而且我确实很想往这方面发展
in art history and I was meant to do something with it,
但我没做到
but I didn't.
不知从什么时候起
Somewhere along the line,
我忘记了追寻自己的梦想 而且
I forgot to pursue my dream, and...
而且我现在都老了 还当妈了 一切都来不及了
and now I'm old and I'm a mom and it's just too late for me.
莉莉 好了 好了
Lily, okay, okay.
-太晚了  -不不 现在还不晚
-It's too late. -No, no, no, it's not too...
现在还不晚
it's not too late.
你明天就去辞掉你的工作
You're gonna quit your job tomorrow,
然后就 就回到你放弃艺术的地方
and you're gonna... you're gonna go back and pick up
把这个梦想重新拾起来
right where you left off with that art stuff.
然后 你听我说
And then you know what?
我会找到谢莉 我会狠狠冲她脸上揍一拳
I'm gonna find Shelly, and I'm gonna punch her in the face.
我会的 我会去揍一个女孩
I am-- I'm gonna punch a girl...
然后赶紧逃
and run away.
听着
Look.
我向你保证
I promise you,
你最美好最激动人心的时刻
your best and your most exciting days
都在未来等着你呢
are all ahead of you.
我真的很爱你这样说
I love you so much for saying that,
但生命里总会有那么一天
but there gets to be a point in life
你说的这些都没机会实现
where that just stops being true.
很抱歉我偷了东西
I'm sorry I stole this.
我明天第一件事就是去归还
I'll return it first thing tomorrow.
于是第二天 莉莉回到
And so the next day, Lily returned
船长的公寓
to the Captain's apartment.
呃 这个怎么说
Well, how about that.
我根本没意识到这玩意丢了
I didn't even realize it was gone.
没啥损失
No harm done.
等等 如果你不是为了这个烟灰缸打电话给我
Wait, if you weren't calling about the ashtray,
那你为什么想见我
then why'd you want to see me?
跟我来
Follow me.
天啊
Oh, my gosh.
是的 那天晚上我又回到画廊
Yep, that night, I ducked back down
把这幅画买了下来
into the gallery and bought it.
谢莉没有阻止你吗
Shelly didn't stop you?
谢莉跟她在派对上遇见的什么皇家大公爵走了
Shelly was off with some archduke she met at the party.
不 我只是... 怎么说呢
No, I just... well,
我喜欢你说的那句 你就是很喜欢这幅画
I liked what you said about how you just liked it.
我现在还是喜欢
I still do.
我也喜欢
Me, too.
不管怎样 我刚把它卖了四百万
Anyway, I just sold it for $4 million.
我勒了去
What?
在我买下这幅画之后不到一年半
In the year and a half since I bought this piece,
那个画家就成为了艺术界的大明星
the artist has turned into a huge star in the art world.
大家都称赞道 他就是下一个巴斯奎特
The next Basquiat, they're saying.517
让•米切尔•巴斯奎特 美国著名涂鸦艺术家
但除了你之外 没有人如此远见卓识
And nobody saw it coming except you.
所以我决定给你一半的卖画收入
So I've decided to give you half my earnings from the sale.
开玩笑的
I'm just kidding.
我不会给你两百万
I'm not giving you two million bucks.
虽然 我可以给你
I mean, I could.
很随意 这对我来说小事一桩
Easily-- it wouldn't even make a dent for me.
但相信我 按现在这样的税率
But trust me, the tax code being what it is,
你肯定不想当有钱人
you do not want to be rich right now.
所以我在想
So here's what I'm thinking.
我想重回艺术收藏界
I want to get back in the art game,
而我需要一个新的艺术顾问
and I need a new art consultant.
等等 你是在给我提供工作吗
Wait, are you offering me a job?
如果你想干的话
If you want it.
你觉得怎么样
What do you say?
然后莉莉答应了 同志们 多么激动人心啊
And she said yes. Guys, it was amazing!
-你们也在场就好了  -巴尼
-You should have been there. -Barney!
-你这次不在场  -让莉莉自己讲完
-You were not there. -Let her tell her story.
别吵了
Guys!
你怎么说的 亲爱的
What did you say, baby?
我答应了
I said yes.
哈 我早说吧
Ha! Told you!
我是怎么知道她答应了的
How would I know that she was going to say...?
大芬维克的皇家大公爵
HIMYM字幕组 谢谢观看